<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<preface version="5.0" xml:id="preface" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:ns5="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:ns4="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:ns3="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:ns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <title>Preface</title>

  <para>The Spring Shell provides an interactive shell that allows you to
  plugin your own custom commands using a Spring based programming
  model.</para>

  <para>The shell has been extracted from the <link
  ns2:href="http://www.springsource.org/spring-roo/">Spring Roo
  project</link>, giving it a strong foundation and rich feature set. One
  significant change from Spring Roo is that the plugin model is no longer
  based on OSGi but instead uses the Spring IoC container to discover commands
  through classpath scanning. There is currently no classloader isolation
  between plugins, however that maybe added in future versions.</para>

  <para>Spring Shell's features include</para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>A simple, annotation driven, programming model to contribute
      custom commands</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>Use of Spring's classpath scanning functionality as the basis for
      a command plugin strategy and command development</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>Inheritance of the <link
      ns2:href="http://static.springsource.org/spring-roo/reference/html-single/index.html#usage-shell">Roo
      Shell features</link>, most notably tab completion, colorization, and
      script execution.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>Customization of command prompt, banner, shell history file
      name.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <para>This document assumes that the reader already has a basic familiarity
  with the Spring Framework.</para>

  <para>While every effort has been made to ensure that this documentation is
  comprehensive and there are no errors, nevertheless some topics might
  require more explanation and some typos might have crept in. If you do spot
  any mistakes or even more serious errors and you can spare a few cycles
  during lunch, please do bring the error to the attention of the Spring Shell
  team by <link ns2:href="https://jira.springsource.org/browse/SHL">raising an
  issue</link>.</para>
</preface>
